Tejinder Singh

SUMMARY

Mechanical Design Engineer interested in pursuing engaging position to implement skills and expertise honed through years of engineering background. Accomplished professional with powerful problem-solving, analytical and communication skills and proven capability to multitask within fiercely competitive and fast-paced environments, ensuring timely completion of projects without compromising quality.

EXPERIENCE

Sheridan College - Draftsman

Brampton , ON • 01/2016 - 12/2018

- Designed injection-molded plastic parts, machined parts and sheet metal parts in 3D CAD.
- Managed assignments and teams working at different stages of diverse project types using AutoCad, Catia, SolidWorks and Inventor.
- Generated detailed 3D models and advanced assemblies, weldments and drawings ahead of schedule and according to department and company guidelines.
- Received and reviewed details from design professionals to determine precise measurements for drawing preparation.
- Created designs using computer programs such as AutoCAD and SolidWorks to complete Pipe Drafting and Design for plant layout.

HPG - CNC Machinist

Milton, ON • 12/2018 - 06/2019

- Observed machines for proper functioning and made adjustments to meet specifications and complete work orders on-time and under budget.
- Worked from layout and work order, created programs and set up machines to produce required parts.
- Adjusted offsets daily based on work orders and changing production needs.
- Loaded and unloaded machines to prevent expensive equipment issues.
- · Changed out aging tools, fixtures and offsets.
- Set-up and operated lathes, mills and grinders to cut raw materials.

CONTACT

Singh.tj944@gmail.com 416-450-6461 Brampton , ON L6T 2N8

SKILLS

- · Schematics reading
- · Equipment set up
- · Tapping and milling
- · CNC and manual equipment
- Tooling and fixtures
- De-burring
- Drilling
- Expertise in AutoCad, Solidworks, Catia and Inventor
- Reading and interpreting blueprints
- SolidWorks modeling
- Process engineering
- · Creative thinking
- · Quality control
- CATIA V5
- AutoCAD expertise
- 3D design and simulation software

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Associate of Applied Science: Tool And Die Central Tool Room Punjab, INDIA • 07/2011

Precision Tool and Die - CNC Machinist

Mississauga, ON • 02/2016 - 08/2016

• Observed machines for proper functioning and made adjustments to meet specifications and complete work orders on-time and under budget.

- Worked from layout and work order, created programs and set up machines to produce required parts.
- Adjusted offsets daily based on work orders and changing production needs.
- Troubleshot machinery and programming issues to exceed production goals.

Magna - CNC Machinist

Mississauga , ON • 09/2016 - 01/2017

- Observed machines for proper functioning and made adjustments to meet specifications and complete work orders on-time and under budget.
- Worked from layout and work order, created programs and set up machines to produce required parts.
- Adjusted offsets daily based on work orders and changing production needs.
- Monitored and adjusted processes or equipment to improve quality and productivity.

High School Diploma Sheridan College Brampton, ON • 12/2018